Writing Multiple Bit-Depth Graphics Code
Using C++ Templates
Jonathan Shekter
Adobe Systems, Inc.

Starting with version 5.0, After Effects supports 16 bit per channel (16bpc) compositing. Effects plug-in writers can take
advantage of this new functionality by writing 16bpc capable effects. However, all effects must also work in on 8bpc
images. Therefore, effects which take advantage of the new higher bit depth must also contain code to perform the same
image processing operation on two different pixel formats.

バージョン5.0以降、After Effectsは16ビット/チャンネル（16bpc）の合成をサポートしています。
 プラグインを書く人が取ることができる効果
16bpc対応の効果を書くことによってこの新しい機能の利点。 ただし、すべての効果は8bpcでまたはたらく必要があります
画像 したがって、新しいより高いビット深度を利用する効果にも、同じことを実行するためのコードが含まれている必要があります。
2つの異なるピクセルフォーマットに対する画像処理操作。


In most cases, the algorithm used for both 8 and 16 bit-per-channel processing will be identical. Ideally, one would like to
write (and maintain) only one copy of any given algorithm. This white paper describes how C++ template programming
techniques may be used to achieve this.

ほとんどの場合、1チャンネルあたり8ビットと16ビットの処理に使用されるアルゴリズムは同じです。 理想的には、与えられたアルゴリズムのコピーを1つだけ書く（そして保守する）。 このホワイトペーパーでは、C ++テンプレートのプログラミング方法について説明します。
これを達成するために技術を使用することができる。

Why Templates?

There a number of approaches to duplicating program logic for different bit depths. Non-template approaches include:
異なるビット深度に対してプログラムロジックを複製することには、いくつかのアプローチがあります。 非テンプレートアプローチには以下が含まれます。

. Copy and paste. This is the simplest of all possible methods, in terms of conceptual complexity. In practice it suffers in
many ways. For instance, the conversion of the copied code from one bit depth to another must be done by hand,
which is tedious and error prone. Worst of all, it requires maintenance of two logically identical bodies of code. Not
only is this time-consuming, but it is problematic in that there is no guarantee that both copies really embody the
same algorithm at any given point during development.
コピーアンドペースト。 概念的な複雑さの点で、これはすべての可能な方法の中で最も単純です。 実際には苦しみます
多くの方法。 たとえば、コピーされたコードのあるビット深度から別のビット深度への変換は手動で行わなければなりません。
これは面倒でエラーが発生しやすくなります。 最悪の場合、2つの論理的に同一のコード本体を保守する必要があります。 ではない
これは時間がかかるだけですが、両方のコピーが本当に時間を費やすという保証がないという点で問題があります。
開発中の任意の時点で同じアルゴリズム。

. Use of the C preprocessor. The most obvious technique in this class would be to describe an entire function as a
#define macro, with a few parameters representing basic types and constants which differ based on bit-depth.
Needless to say, this is very awkward.
Cプリプロセッサの使用 このクラスで最も明白なテクニックは、関数全体を
#defineマクロ。基本的な型を表すいくつかのパラメータと、ビット深度によって異なる定数を表します。
言うまでもなく、これは非常に厄介です。

. A more sophisticated preprocessor method involves writing a separate file which is #included in a main source file
after defining macros for types, constants, accessor and arithmetic functions, etc. This overcomes the problems of the
copy & paste approach, in that there is only one source level implementation of any given function, but it is still
somewhat awkward. Besides being hard to read (in that the multiple bit-depth code cannot be written “normally”)
some debuggers cannot step through code written in this way.
より洗練されたプリプロセッサメソッドは、メインソースファイルに含まれている別のファイルを書くことを含みます。
型、定数、アクセサ、算術関数などのマクロを定義した後。
コピー＆ペーストのアプローチ、任意の関数のソースレベルの実装は1つだけですが、それでもまだ
ややぎこちない。 読みづらいことに加えて（マルチビット深度コードは「普通に」書くことができないという点で）
このように書かれたコードをステップスルーできないデバッガもあります。

. From an object-oriented viewpoint, pixels can be viewed as polymorphic objects which support a certain set of
operations. C++ supports polymorphism through virtual functions, and one can define pixel objects through an
abstract base class with virtual functions to perform basic processing and arithmetic operations. This is standard,
simple, and elegant, but it exacts a heavy performance penalty. Namely, every pixel object must carry a virtual
function table pointer, which is a huge overhead for a small pixel structure, and all arithmetic must be performed
through virtual function calls, which are very expensive for operations which might otherwise require only a single
machine instruction.
オブジェクト指向の観点からは、ピクセルは特定のセットのセットをサポートする多相オブジェクトとして見ることができます。
オペレーション。 C ++は仮想関数を介して多態性をサポートしています。
基本処理と算術演算を実行するための仮想関数を持つ抽象基本クラス。 これは標準です、
シンプルでエレガントですが、パフォーマンスが非常に低下します。 つまり、すべてのピクセルオブジェクトは仮想の
関数テーブルポインタ。これは小さなピクセル構造にとっては大きなオーバーヘッドであり、すべての算術演算を実行する必要があります。
仮想関数呼び出しによるもの
機械命令

Thus, without templates, there is no technique which avoids duplicate code while remaining simple, standard,
maintainable, and highly efficient.
したがって、テンプレートがなければ、単純で標準的なままで重複コードを回避する手法はありません。
維持可能、そして非常に効率的。



Basic Template Usage
The basics of template syntax and usage can be found in any good C++ book. To apply this to the problem at hand,
consider the following function which performs some image processing operation on a pixel buffer:
テンプレートの構文と使用方法の基本は、優れたC ++の本にあります。 これを当面の問題に適用するには、
ピクセルバッファに対して何らかの画像処理操作を実行する次の関数を考えてください。

	void ProcessPixels(PF_Pixel *in, int len, PF_Pixel *out)
	{
		PF_Pixel *ptr = in;
		while (len--) {
			// Do something to pixels…
		}
	}
This is what a scanline processing routine written for AE’s usual 8 bit-per-channel PF_Pixel type might look like. The 16 bit
version of this code should perform the logically identical operation, but on a different pixel type. Such a routine might
look like this:
これが、AEの通常のチャンネルあたり8ビットのPF_Pixelタイプ用に書かれたスキャンライン処理ルーチンのようなものです。 16ビット
このコードのバージョンは、論理的に同じ操作を実行する必要がありますが、ピクセルタイプが異なります。 そのようなルーチンは
こんな風に見える：

	void ProcessPixels(PF_Pixel16 *in, int len, PF_Pixel16 *out)
	{
		PF_Pixel16 *ptr = in;
		while (len--) {
			// Do something to pixels…
		}
	}
(Note that we haven’t changed the actual name of the routine, in other words were using function overloading here. The
compiler will automatically determine the correct function to invoke whenever this symbol is called, based on the types of
the arguments. This property will prove very useful in templated code.)
（このルーチンの実際の名前は変更していません。つまり、ここでは関数オーバーロードを使用していました。
このシンボルが呼び出されるたびに、コンパイラは次の型に基づいて起動する正しい関数を自動的に決定します。
引数 このプロパティはテンプレート化されたコードで非常に役に立つでしょう。）


So far so good, but as discussed above we’d really like to avoid manually duplicating code. This can be accomplished by
replacing both of the above functions with the following templated definition:
これまでのところ非常に優れていますが、上で説明したように、手作業でコードを複製することは避けたいと思います。 これはによって達成することができます
上記の両方の機能を次のテンプレート定義で置き換えます。


	template <typename PIXTYPE>
	void ProcessPixels(PIXTYPE *in, int len, PIXTYPE *out)
	{
		PIXTYPE *ptr = in;
		while (len--) {
			// Do something to pixels…
		}
	}



The PIXTYPE symbol is known as a “template parameter” and stands for an unknown type. After the “template” line,
PIXTYPE acts just like a typedef. Parameters and return values may be declared to have this type, and it can be used for
local variable definitions within the body of the function. However, no object code is actually generated when the compiler
encounters this definition. Only when this function is actually called will code be generated. At that point, the type of the
PIXTYPE parameter is determined based on the arguments to the call, and object code will be produced for a function
which acts on that type. This process is called “instantiation” and is usually handled automatically by the compiler.
PIXTYPEシンボルは「テンプレートパラメータ」と呼ばれ、未知のタイプを表します。 「template」行の後PIXTYPEはtypedefと同じように機能します。 パラメータと戻り値は、この型を持つように宣言することができます。
関数本体内のローカル変数定義 ただし、コンパイラを実行しても実際にはオブジェクトコードは生成されません。
この定義に出会う。 この関数が実際に呼び出されたときにのみコードが生成されます。 その時点では、PIXTYPEパラメータは呼び出しの引数に基づいて決定され、オブジェクトコードは関数に対して生成されます。
それはそのタイプに作用します。 このプロセスは「インスタンス化」と呼ばれ、通常はコンパイラによって自動的に処理されます。


Within an After Effects plug-in, one might call the above function as follows:
After Effectsプラグイン内では、上記の関数を次のように呼び出すことができます。

	PF_World *input_world, *output_world;
	if (PF_WORLD_IS_DEEP(input_world))
		ProcessPixels(
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA16(input_world),
			input_world->width,
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA16(output_world));
	else
		ProcessPixels(
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA8(input_world),
			input_world->width,
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA8(output_world));

Because the PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA8 and PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA16 macros evaluate to an expression of type PF_Pixel8* and
PF_Pixel16*, respectively, the compiler instantiates ProcessPixels() on these two types. Note that each templated function
is instantiated at most once for each type; all calls with the same argument types will bind to the same instantiation. The
net result is that the same source code function generates exactly as many different object code functions as there are
different pixel types, no matter how many times it is called, which is exactly the desired behavior.
PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA8およびPF_GET_PIXEL_DATA16マクロは、タイプPF_Pixel8 *および
それぞれ、PF_Pixel16 *は、これら2つの型のProcessPixels（）をインスタンス化します。 各テンプレート関数は
型ごとに最大1回インスタンス化されます。 同じ引数型を持つすべての呼び出しは、同じインスタンス化にバインドされます。 の
最終的には、同じソースコード関数が正確に同じ数の異なるオブジェクトコード関数を生成します。
たとえ何回呼び出されても、異なるピクセルタイプは、まさに望ましい振る舞いです。

Using an Unknown Type

Suppose one wanted to write a function that performs clipped addition of a span of pixel values. An 8-bit version might
あるピクセル値の範囲のクリップ加算を実行する関数を書きたいとします。 8ビットバージョン

look like this:
	void AddSpan(PF_Pixel *in, int len, PF_Pixel *out)
	{
		while (len--) {
			out->red = min((int)in->red + (int)out->red, 255)
			.
			.
			.
		}
	}

This can be templated easily enough, but different pixel types will have different maximum values, so the constant 255 in
the above function will be incorrect. More generally, this sort of problem occurs whenever merely changing the type of the
pixel parameters and variable is not sufficient to convert an algorithm from 8 to 16 bits.
これは十分に簡単にテンプレート化することができますが、異なるピクセルタイプは異なる最大値を持ちます。
上記の機能は正しくありません。 もっと一般的に言えば、この種の問題は単にタイプを変更するだけで発生します
ピクセルパラメータと変数は、8から16ビットにアルゴリズムを変換するのに十分ではありません。


Using Unknown Types Through Overloaded Functions
多重定義関数による未知の型の使用

One solution to this problem involves defining overloaded functions to perform bit-depth specific manipulations. For
この問題に対する１つの解決策は、ビット深度特有の操作を実行するために過負荷関数を定義することを含む。 にとって

example, one could write:

	// 8 bit version
	inline void AddPixel(PF_Pixel8 *src, PF_Pixel8 *dst)
	{
		out->red = min((int)in->red + (int)out->red, 255)
		out->green = min((int)in->green + (int)out->green, 255)
		out->blue = min((int)in->blue + (int)out->blue, 255)
		out->alpha = min((int)in->alpha + (int)out->alpha, 255)
	}
	// 16 bit version
	inline void AddPixel(PF_Pixel16 *src, PF_Pixel16 *dst)
	{
		out->red = min((int)in->red + (int)out->red, 32768)
		out->green = min((int)in->green + (int)out->green, 32768)
		out->blue = min((int)in->blue + (int)out->blue, 32768)
		out->alpha = min((int)in->alpha + (int)out->alpha, 32768)
	}
	
Then, a templated span addition routine can be written by exploiting C++’s function overload mechanism:
それから、C ++の関数オーバーロードメカニズムを利用して、テンプレート化されたスパン追加ルーチンを書くことができます。

	template <typename PIXTYPE>
	void AddSpan(PIXTYPE *in, int len, PIXTYPE *out)
	{
		while (len--) {
			AddPixel(in, out);
			in++;
			out++;
		}
	}
When AddSpan() is instantiated for a particular pixel type, the compiler will automatically determine which version of
AddPixel() to call based on the type of the pointers passed to it, which in turn will have type corresponding to the template
parameter PIXTYPE.
定のピクセルタイプに対してAddSpan（）がインスタンス化されると、コンパイラは自動的にどのバージョンのバージョンかを判断します。
渡されたポインタの型に基づいて呼び出すAddPixel（）、つまりテンプレートに対応する型になります。
パラメータPIXTYPE。

This works, and is elegant and simple when the required code varies greatly between pixel types. A good example of this
would be an algorithm where some computational step is performed by accessing a look-up-table when operating on 8 bit
pixels, but computed directly for 16 bit pixels (presumably because a 32769 element table would take too much memory.)
By encapsulating this step into two different overloaded functions, the algorithmic difference between the two bit depths
can be hidden from the main processing.
これはうまく機能し、必要なコードがピクセルタイプ間で大きく異なる場合にはエレガントでシンプルです。 この良い例
8ビットで動作しているときにルックアップテーブルにアクセスすることによって何らかの計算ステップが実行されるアルゴリズムです。
ただし、16ビットピクセルの場合は直接計算されます（おそらく32769の要素テーブルではメモリが多すぎるためです）。
このステップを2つの異なるオーバーロード関数にカプセル化することによって、2つのビット深度間のアルゴリズムの違い
メイン処理から隠すことができます。


However, when the 8 and 16 bit versions of some operation are very similar, as in the case above, it’s not an entirely
satisfactory solution. For instance, the same operation is often performed on multiple image channels, so it would be nice
to encapsulate the differences in processing at the channel level, rather than the pixel level. One might try overloading on
channel type:
ただし、上記の場合のように、ある操作の8ビットバージョンと16ビットバージョンが非常によく似ている場合、それは完全なものではありません。
満足のいく解決策。 例えば、同じ操作がしばしば複数の画像チャンネルで実行されるので、それはいいでしょう
ピクセルレベルではなく、チャンネルレベルで処理の違いをカプセル化します。 過負荷を試してみるかもしれません
チャンネルの種類

	// DANGEROUS! Don’t do this! See text below.
	inline uchar AddChannel(uchar a, uchar b)
	{
		return min((int)a + (int)b, 255); // 8 bit version
	}
	// DANGEROUS! Don’t do this! See text below.
	inline ushort AddChannel(ushort a, ushort b)
	{
		return min((int)a + (int)b, 32768); // 16 bit version
	}

but this is a very bad idea. The problem is that channel values aren’t always represented by the “obvious” type. Larger
intermediate types are required for many types of computation (as in the casts to int in the additions above) and there’s no
easy way to guarantee that no one will ever store your 8-bit pixel value in a 16-bit type. Consider:
しかしこれは非常に悪い考えです。 問題は、チャンネルの値が必ずしも「明白な」タイプで表されるとは限らないことです。 大きい
中間型は、（上記の追加のintへのキャストのように）多くの種類の計算に必要です。
誰もあなたの8ビットピクセル値を16ビットタイプに格納しないことを保証するための簡単な方法。 検討してください：

	template <typename PIXTYPE>
	void DoSomething(PIXTYPE *ptr)
	{
		ushort stored_red = ptr->red;
		ushort stored_blue = ptr->blue;
		ptr->green = AddChannel(stored_red, stored_blue);
	}

In this example, the arguments to the AddChannel() call will always be of type ushort, no matter what size pixels this
function is actually instantiated on. Thus, the 16-bit version of AddChannel() will be called even when processing 8 bit
pixels! The situation gets even more confusing when the arguments to AddChannel() have different types. In such cases, at
best you’ll get an error message from the compiler complaining about ambiguous function overload resolution. At worst,
C/C++’s integral type promotion rules will be invoked silently and the wrong function will be called. Of course, any
individual line of code can be fixed to overcome these problems, but the general technique is very error-prone and fragile.
この例では、AddChannel（）呼び出しの引数は、これがどのサイズのピクセルであっても常にushort型になります。
関数は実際にはインスタンス化されています。 したがって、16ビットバージョンのAddChannel（）は、8ビットを処理する場合でも呼び出されます。
ピクセル！ AddChannel（）の引数の型が異なると、状況はさらに複雑になります。 そのような場合は、
あいまいな関数のオーバーロード解決について文句を言うエラーメッセージがコンパイラから出てくるのが一番です。 最悪の場合、C / C ++の整数型の昇格規則は暗黙のうちに呼び出され、間違った関数が呼び出されます。 もちろん、どれでもこれらの問題を克服するために個々のコード行を修正することができますが、一般的な手法は非常にエラーが発生しやすく脆弱です。

In summary, performing some operation on an unknown (template parameter) type by function overloading is an excellent strategy when entire pixels are being processed substantially differently depending on bit depth, but is inelegant or downright dangerous for more atomic operations such as channel arithmetic.
まとめると、関数のオーバーロードによって未知の（テンプレートパラメータ）型に対して何らかの演算を実行することは、ビット深度に応じてピクセル全体が実質的に異なる方法で処理されている場合に優れた戦略です。


Traits Classes The above problems with AddSpan() could be solved if there were some way to know the maximum channel value within the function in a parameterized way. More generally, there are many things one would like to associate with a given pixel type, such as:
特性クラスAddSpan（）に関する上記の問題は、パラメータ化された方法で関数内の最大チャネル値を知る方法があれば解決できます。 より一般的には、与えられたピクセルタイプに関連付けたいものがたくさんあります。

. bit depth ビット深度
. minimum, maximum, and half channel values 
  最小、最大、および半チャネル値
. channel type 
. intermediate types (useful for channel arithmetic) 
  中間型（チャネル演算に便利）
. optimized functions for basic channel arithmetic (multiplication, etc.)
  基本的なチャネル演算（乗算など）用に最適化された関数


Although not currently supported in After Effects, this list could even include things like number of channels, color-space,
whether the alpha is straight or premultiplied, etc.
現在After Effectsではサポートされていませんが、このリストにはチャンネル数、カラースペース、
アルファがストレートかどうか

All of this “stuff” can be stored in a “traits” class, a concept first developed for use in the C++ standard library (formerly
known as the Standard Template Library.) This involves defining a structure which holds all these constants, types, and functions:
これらすべての「もの」は、「traits」クラスに格納することができます。これは、C ++標準ライブラリ（旧称）で使用するために最初に開発された概念です。
これは、標準テンプレートライブラリとして知られています。）これには、次の定数、型、および関数すべてを保持する構造体を定義することが含まれます。

	struct PF_Pixel8_Traits {
		enum { bit_depth = 8; }
		enum { max_value = 255; }
		typedef uchar channel_type;
		static uchar Multiply(uchar a, uchar b);
		...
	};
	
	struct PF_Pixel16_Traits {
		enum { bit_depth = 16; }
		enum { max_value = 32768; }
		typedef ushort channel_type;
		static ushort Multiply(ushort a, ushort b);
		...
	};
Note that these structures have no data and therefore no non-static methods. They are merely a description of a particular
type. Because of this, passing a traits object to a function is usually a no-op, depending on the compiler’s optimizer. With
such a structure in hand, all the relevant particulars about a pixel type can be conveniently packaged into a single
parameter, like this:
これらの構造体にはデータがないため、非静的メソッドはありません。 それらは単に特定のものの説明です
タイプ。 このため、traitsオブジェクトを関数に渡すことは、コンパイラのオプティマイザにもよりますが、通常は何もしません。 あり
このような構造を手にすると、ピクセルタイプに関するすべての関連項目を1つのパッケージにまとめて便利にまとめることができます。
このようなパラメータ：

	template <typename PIXTYPE, typename TRAITS>
	void ProcessPixels(PIXTYPE *in, int len, PIXTYPE *out, TRAITS traits_obj)
	{
		// Declare local variables of channel type
		// (C++ standard says we need “typename” keyword here to denote
		// a template-derived type, and some compilers complain without it.)
		typename TRAITS::channel_type red, green, blue, alpha;
		.
		.
		while (len--) {
			.
			.
			// Clip to pixel type’s max value
			out->red = min((int)in->red + (int)out->red, TRAITS::max_value);
			.
			.
			// Multiply two channels together
			product = TRAITS:Multiply(in->red, in->alpha);
			.
			.
			// etc.
		}
	}
This shows declaration of variables which have type dependent on the traits class, and access of constants and functions
within the traits class. Because all channel arithmetic function calls are now methods of the traits class, there is no integral
type ambiguity as there was with overloaded functions in the global scope. Note that the actual traits_obj is never used,
only its type matters. This routine would be called as follows:
これは、特性クラスに依存する型を持つ変数の宣言、および定数と関数のアクセスを示しています。
特性クラス内 すべてのチャンネル算術関数呼び出しはtraitsクラスのメソッドになったので、整数はありません。
グローバルスコープのオーバーロードされた関数にあったように型のあいまいさ。 実際のtraits_objは決して使われないことに注意してください。
その種類だけが重要です。 このルーチンは次のように呼び出されます。

	PF_World *input_world, *output_world;
	if (PF_WORLD_IS_DEEP(input_world))
		ProcessPixels(
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA16(input_world),
			input_world->width,
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA16(output_world),
			PF_Pixel16_Traits());
	else
		ProcessPixels(
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA8(input_world),
			input_world->width,
			PF_GET_PIXEL_DATA8(output_world),
			PF_Pixel8_Traits());

Associating Traits With Types
This is effective, but still somewhat awkward. In particular a traits object must be passed down the call chain through all
templated functions. This makes things like callbacks or function pointers difficult to use. Also, there is no guarantee that
traits object will always match the pixel type; it’s perfectly possible to pass a PF_Pixel8_Traits object to a routine which is
processing 16 bit pixels. The resulting object code will be totally incorrect but will probably compile without generating any warnings.
これは効果的ですが、やや厄介です。 特に、traitsオブジェクトはallを通してcall chainに渡されなければなりません。
テンプレート関数 これはコールバックや関数ポインタのようなものを使いにくくします。 また、という保証はありません。
traitsオブジェクトは常にピクセルタイプと一致します。 PF_Pixel8_Traitsオブジェクトを次のようなルーチンに渡すことは完全に可能です。
16ビットピクセルを処理します。 結果のオブジェクトコードはtになります。

What is needed is a way to associate a traits object with pixel types. Then, this association could be invoked within each
function, removing the need to pass an empty object down the call stack and preventing type mismatch errors.
必要なのは、traitsオブジェクトをピクセルタイプと関連付ける方法です。 それから、この関連付けはそれぞれの中で呼び出すことができます。
空のオブジェクトを呼び出しスタックに渡す必要がなくなり、型の不一致エラーを防ぐことができます。

This can be accomplished through the mechanism of class template specialization. Rather than defining the traits class for
each pixel type as a separate class, they are defined as specializations of some (never used, undefined) templated class
definition:
これは、クラステンプレートの特殊化のメカニズムを通じて実現できます。 の特性クラスを定義するのではなくそれぞれのピクセル型を別々のクラスとして、それらはいくつかの（決して使われていない、未定義の）テンプレートクラスの特殊化として定義されています
定義：
	// template class declaration; no default definition provided
	template <typename PIXTYPE>
	struct PixelTraits;
	// Specialize on PF_Pixel8 to define 8 bpc traits
	template <>
	struct PixelTraits<PF_Pixel8> {
		enum { bit_depth = 8; }
		enum { max_value = 255; }
		typedef uchar channel_type;
		static uchar Multiply(uchar a, uchar b);
		...
		};
		// Specialize on PF_Pixel16 to define 16 bpc traits
		template <>
		struct PixelTraits<PF_Pixel16> {
		enum { bit_depth = 16; }
		enum { max_value = 32768; }
		typedef ushort channel_type;
		static ushort Multiply(ushort a, ushort b);
		...
	};

We can now refer to the traits class for a template parameter PIXTYPE by writing “PixTraits<PIXTYPE>”. This name is valid
at any scope, including inside a function, so
there is no need to actually pass an object of this type into pixel processing functions; the passed object wasn’t actually
used anyway. AddSpan() now looks like this:
“ PixTraits <PIXTYPE>”と書くことでテンプレートパラメータPIXTYPEのトレイトクラスを参照することができます。 この名前は有効です
関数の中も含めて、あらゆる範囲で
実際にこのタイプのオブジェクトをピクセル処理関数に渡す必要はありません。 渡されたオブジェクトは実際にはなかった
とにかく使用されます。 AddSpan（）はこのようになりました：

	template <typename PIXTYPE>
	void AddSpan(PIXTYPE *in, int len, PIXTYPE *out)
	{
		while (len--) {
			out->red = min((int)in->red + int)out->red,
							PixelTraits<PIXTYPE>::max_value);
			out->green = min((int)in->green + int)out->green,
							PixelTraits<PIXTYPE>::max_value);
			out->blue = min((int)in->blue + int)out->blue,
						PixelTraits<PIXTYPE>::max_value);
			out->alpha = min((int)in->alpha + int)out->alpha,
						PixelTraits<PIXTYPE>::max_value);
			in++;
			out++;
		}
	}
Ideally, we’d add an “AddChannel” method to the traits class, which performs the appropriate clipped addition. Along with
shorter symbol names (“PT” for “PixelTraits” and “P” for “PIXTYPE”) complex multiple bit-depth code can become quite
readable:
理想的には、適切なクリップ追加を実行する「AddChannel」メソッドをtraitsクラスに追加します。 に加えて
短いシンボル名（ "PixelTraits"の場合は "PT"、 "PIXTYPE"の場合は "P"）は、複雑なマルチビット深度コードになります。
読める

	template <typename P>
	void AddSpan(P *in, int len, P *out)
	{
		while (len--) {
		out->red = PT<P>::AddChannel(in->red , out->red );
		out->green = PT<P>::AddChannel(in->green , out->green);
		out->blue = PT<P>::AddChannel(in->blue , out->blue );
		out->alpha = PT<P>::AddChannel(in->alpha , out->alpha);
		in++;
		out++;
		}
	}
When this function is instantiated, the compiler will resolve the symbol “PT<P>” to the correct traits class, and use this to
select the types, constants, and functions appropriate to the current pixel type. Because all of this is done based on static
type at compile time, this process invokes no run-time overhead. With the inlining of pixel arithmetic methods, the code
generated is perfectly optimal, in the sense that it is just as efficient as pre-processor generated functions or hand-coded
cut & paste routines.
この関数がインスタンス化されると、コンパイラはシンボル“ PT <P>”を正しい特性クラスに解決し、これを使って以下のようにします。
現在のピクセルタイプに適したタイプ、定数、関数を選択してください。 これはすべて静的に基づいて行われるためです。
コンパイル時にタイプすると、このプロセスは実行時のオーバーヘッドを発生させません。 ピクセル算術メソッドのインライン化により、コードは
プリプロセッサで生成された関数やハンドコードと同じくらい効率的であるという意味で、generatedは完全に最適です。
カット＆ペーストルーチン
Summary

C++’s function template mechanism seems ideally suited to the problem of writing high-performance low-level graphics
code which operates on multiple bit-depths. In particular, templates are specifically designed to produce multiple,
individually optimized object-code routines to be generated from a single readable source-code function.
C ++の関数テンプレートメカニズムは、高性能の低レベルグラフィックスを書くという問題に理想的に適しているようです。
複数のビット深度で動作するコード。 特に、テンプレートは複数を生成するように特別に設計されています。
単一の読み取り可能なソースコード関数から生成される、個々に最適化されたオブジェクトコードルーチン。

Unfortunately, applying templates to basic pixel structures is not as simple as it seems, because the concept of “bit depth”
involves a lot more than just a single pixel type. In particular, numerous types, constants, and basic arithmetic functions
are bit-depth specific.
残念ながら、基本的なピクセル構造にテンプレートを適用することは、「ビット深度」の概念であるため、見かけほど単純ではありません。
単一のピクセルタイプだけではありません。 特に、多数の型、定数、および基本算術関数
ビット深度固有です。

Large algorithmic differences between bit depths can be effectively handled through function overloading. However this
method is inadequate for handling for finer-grained operations, such as channel arithmetic, where the base pixel type is
not explicitly used. The problem of inferring types, constants, and methods associated with the base pixel type is therefore
best solved through the use of traits classes.
ビット深度間の大きなアルゴリズムの違いは、関数のオーバーロードによって効果的に処理できます。 しかしこれ
この方法は、基本ピクセルタイプが次のようなチャネル算術などのよりきめの細かい操作の処理には不十分です。
明示的には使用されていません。 したがって、基本ピクセルタイプに関連するタイプ、定数、およびメソッドを推論する問題は
特性クラスを使用することによって最もよく解決されます。

The resulting syntax is a little awkward in places, but overall templates provide the best tradeoff between performance
and clarity. That is, the performance is optimal, and templates are much easier to write, read, debug, and maintain than
other techniques such as preprocessor tricks.
結果として得られる構文は場所によっては少々扱いにくいですが、全体的なテンプレートはパフォーマンス間の最良のトレードオフを提供します。
そして明快さ。 つまり、パフォーマンスは最適であり、テンプレートは書き込み、読み取り、デバッグ、および保守がはるかに簡単です。
プリプロセッサトリックのような他のテクニック。

